[
  {
    "question": "Famous skier who won the World Cup 8 times in a row?",
    "answer": "Marcel Hirscher"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many gold medals did American swimmer Mark Spitz win at the 1972 Olympic Games?",
    "answer": "7 medals"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which city did Savonarola preach?",
    "answer": "Florence"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which field did James Watson work?",
    "answer": "genetics"
  },
  {
    "question": "On which island was John the Theologian exiled?",
    "answer": "Patmos"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which order did Ignatius of Loyola belong?",
    "answer": "Jesuits"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did John Dalton develop?",
    "answer": "Atomic theory"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Stepan Timofeyevich Demyanov study?",
    "answer": "physics"
  },
  {
    "question": "What discovery is attributed to Henri Becquerel?",
    "answer": "Radioactivity"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Bob Dylan's real name?",
    "answer": "Robert Zimmerman"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the gathering of cardinals called?",
    "answer": "Conclave"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of David Bowie's first album?",
    "answer": "David Bowie"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Mozart's first studio opera?",
    "answer": "Bastien and Bastienne"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the British designer known for his extremely exclusive and eccentric approach to hats?",
    "answer": "Philip Treacy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the artist who created 'The Feast of the Gods'?",
    "answer": "Giovanni Bellini"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the artist who is considered a central figure in the development of Post-Impressionism?",
    "answer": "Paul Cézanne"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the current head designer of the Saint Laurent brand?",
    "answer": "Anthony Vaccarello"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the designer known for his unique approach to evening fashion using antique motifs?",
    "answer": "John Galliano"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the designer who first created the transparent dress?",
    "answer": "André Courrèges"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the famous British designer who founded the brand Alexander McQueen?",
    "answer": "Lee Alexander McQueen"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the first keyboardist of the band Pink Floyd?",
    "answer": "Richard Wright"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the novel by Yuri Olesha?",
    "answer": "Envy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the series of symphonies written by Mahler?",
    "answer": "Mahler's Symphonies"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the title of Vladimir Nabokov's first published novella?",
    "answer": "Mary"
  },
  {
    "question": "What law did Johannes Kepler discover?",
    "answer": "Law of planetary motion"
  },
  {
    "question": "What musical genre does the music of the band Eloy belong to?",
    "answer": "Symphonic rock"
  },
  {
    "question": "What profession did Hubert de Givenchy pursue?",
    "answer": "Couturier"
  },
  {
    "question": "What technique did Henri de Toulouse-Lautrec use in his works?",
    "answer": "Lithography"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Genghis Khan called before he took this name?",
    "answer": "Temujin"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of Dmitry Donskoy's mother?",
    "answer": "Eudoxia"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of Perseus's chief advisor?",
    "answer": "Amphictyon"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of Tom Cruise's first wife?",
    "answer": "Mimi Rogers"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the artist known for her still lifes?",
    "answer": "Clara Peeters"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the author of the series of paintings 'Sketches'?",
    "answer": "Whistler"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the author of the series of paintings 'Winter Views'?",
    "answer": "Ferdinand Hodler"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the first Pope?",
    "answer": "Peter"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the first guitarist of The Rolling Stones?",
    "answer": "Brian Jones"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the founder of the Pentecostal movement?",
    "answer": "Charles Parham"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the legendary Italian motorcyclist who won 9 titles in MotoGP?",
    "answer": "Valentino Rossi"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the legendary Olympic swimmer from the USSR?",
    "answer": "Vladimir Salnikov"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the long jump champion who held the world record for 23 years?",
    "answer": "Bob Beamon"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the main character in 'Wind's Lullaby'?",
    "answer": "Vladimir"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the title of Dante's first work?",
    "answer": "The New Life"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which British designer is known for conceptual shows?",
    "answer": "Alexander McQueen"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Spanish painter is known as a representative of the Golden Age?",
    "answer": "Diego Velázquez"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which actress played the role of Ginny Weasley?",
    "answer": "Bonnie Wright"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which artist created 'Mixed Bouquet'?",
    "answer": "Jan van Huysum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which artist is associated with the Futurism movement?",
    "answer": "Boccioni"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which artist is considered one of the founders of Dadaism?",
    "answer": "Marcel Duchamp"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which artist is considered the founder of the Northern Renaissance?",
    "answer": "Van Eyck"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which artist is known as a master of still life?",
    "answer": "Paul Cézanne"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which artist is known for his paintings featuring cardsharps?",
    "answer": "Georges de La Tour"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which brand is famous for using rhinestones?",
    "answer": "Dolce & Gabbana"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which city is considered the hometown of Pope Leo I?",
    "answer": "Rome"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which designer became famous for their ethnic collections?",
    "answer": "John Galliano"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which designer created a dress using vinyl and metallic structures?",
    "answer": "Paco Rabanne"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which designer created the mini-skirt?",
    "answer": "Mary Quant"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which designer founded the brand Moncler?",
    "answer": "René Ramillon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which designer introduced the concept of prêt-à-porter?",
    "answer": "Pierre Cardin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which designer is famous for their avant-garde and Japanese style?",
    "answer": "Yohji Yamamoto"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which designer is known for incorporating natural motifs in his collections?",
    "answer": "Alexander McQueen"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which designer is most famous for their work with leather and sewing?",
    "answer": "Rick Owens"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which designer often uses ethnic motifs?",
    "answer": "Gianfranco Ferré"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which designer popularized couture in Japan?",
    "answer": "Yohji Yamamoto"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which designer popularized the androgynous style?",
    "answer": "Rick Owens"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which designer was nicknamed 'the magnificent surrealist'?",
    "answer": "Elsa Schiaparelli"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which designer was the first to originally adapt the unisex style in fashion?",
    "answer": "Giorgio Armani"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which designer was the first to present a plus-size women's clothing collection?",
    "answer": "Christian Siriano"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which director made the film 'Pi'?",
    "answer": "Darren Aronofsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which famous Persian artist created 'The Deer Hunt'?",
    "answer": "Behzad"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which famous designer was behind the brand 'Hervé Léger'?",
    "answer": "Hervé Peugnet"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which famous designer worked as a taxi driver?",
    "answer": "Ralph Lauren"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which gymnast won four gold medals at the 1984 Olympics?",
    "answer": "Mary Lou Retton"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which hypothesis did Grigori Perelman prove?",
    "answer": "Poincaré conjecture"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which model is known for her 'gap-toothed' appearance?",
    "answer": "Lauren Hutton"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which model was Gianni Versace's muse?",
    "answer": "Claudia Schiffer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poet wrote the poem 'A Cloud in Trousers'?",
    "answer": "Vladimir Mayakovsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which science is associated with James Dewar?",
    "answer": "Cryogenics"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which supermodel was nicknamed 'The Chameleon'?",
    "answer": "Linda Evangelista"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who became a legend in retro F1 racing by winning 5 titles?",
    "answer": "Juan Manuel Fangio"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who became the first world champion in billiards?",
    "answer": "Thomas Péraire"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who became the youngest World Chess Champion?",
    "answer": "Garry Kasparov"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed 'A Requiem'?",
    "answer": "John Rutter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed 'Orpheus in the Underworld'?",
    "answer": "Offenbach"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed 'Rigoletto'?",
    "answer": "Giuseppe Verdi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed 'Sailing Wind'?",
    "answer": "Claude Debussy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed 'Spring Waters'?",
    "answer": "Sergei Rachmaninoff"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed Symphony No. 3 'Eroica'?",
    "answer": "Ludwig van Beethoven"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed Symphony No. 4?",
    "answer": "Brahms"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the \"Russian Dance\"?",
    "answer": "Stravinsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the 'Finnish Symphony'?",
    "answer": "Jean Sibelius"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the 'Jupiter' Symphony?",
    "answer": "Mozart"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the 'Mahler Symphonies'?",
    "answer": "Gustav Mahler"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the 'Symphonie fantastique'?",
    "answer": "Berlioz"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the 'Trio for Violin, Oboe, and Piano'?",
    "answer": "Francis Poulenc"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the cantata 'Carmina Burana'?",
    "answer": "Carl Orff"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the opera \"Salome\"?",
    "answer": "Richard Strauss"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the opera 'Boris Godunov'?",
    "answer": "Modest Mussorgsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the opera 'Oedipus Rex'?",
    "answer": "Stravinsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who conducted the New York Philharmonic Orchestra?",
    "answer": "Bruno Walter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created 'Her Height'?",
    "answer": "Boris Kustodiev"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created 'The Dance of Death'?",
    "answer": "Hans Holbein the Younger"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created the 'Missionary Sword'?",
    "answer": "Friedrich"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created the 'grunge' style in fashion?",
    "answer": "Marc Jacobs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created the painting 'The Last Day of Pompeii'?",
    "answer": "Karl Bryullov"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created the panel 'Triptych'?",
    "answer": "Hieronymus Bosch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who declared India's independence in 1947?",
    "answer": "Jawaharlal Nehru"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who developed the Mendeleev table for cosmic objects?",
    "answer": "Ananas Meral"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who developed the Theory of Relativity?",
    "answer": "Albert Einstein"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who developed the concept of 'Couture Sky'?",
    "answer": "Christian Dior"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who developed the concept of 'anti-fashion'?",
    "answer": "Yohji Yamamoto"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who developed the theory of quantum mechanics?",
    "answer": "Werner Heisenberg"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who developed the theory of supergravity?",
    "answer": "Gofffried Grugo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who directed the film 'Breakfast at Tiffany's'?",
    "answer": "Blake Edwards"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who directed the film 'Pan's Labyrinth'?",
    "answer": "Guillermo del Toro"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who directed the film 'Shutter Island' (2010)?",
    "answer": "Martin Scorsese"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who directed the film 'There Will Be Blood'?",
    "answer": "Paul Thomas Anderson"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who directed the movie \"Hotel for Dogs\"?",
    "answer": "Thor Freudenthal"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who directed the movie 'Gravity'?",
    "answer": "Alfonso Cuarón"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who directed the movie 'Maleficent'?",
    "answer": "Robert Stromberg"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who discovered the dual nature of light?",
    "answer": "Christiaan Huygens"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who discovered the structure of the benzene molecule?",
    "answer": "Friedrich August Kekulé"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who first studied blood circulation?",
    "answer": "William Harvey"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who formulated the first law of thermodynamics?",
    "answer": "Rudolf Clausius"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who founded Taoism?",
    "answer": "Laozi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who founded the Bauhaus school?",
    "answer": "Walter Gropius"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who founded the British East India Company?",
    "answer": "Elizabeth I"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who founded the Church of Satan?",
    "answer": "Anton LaVey"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who founded the Mongol Empire?",
    "answer": "Genghis Khan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who founded the Pentecostal movement?",
    "answer": "Charles Parham"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who founded the abstract art style?",
    "answer": "Wassily Kandinsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who founded the brand Comme des Garçons?",
    "answer": "Rei Kawakubo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who founded the company Maison Margiela?",
    "answer": "Martin Margiela"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who founded the famous fashion house known for its feminine aesthetics and intricate draping?",
    "answer": "Madeleine Vionnet"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who gave the order to bomb Hiroshima?",
    "answer": "Harry Truman"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who has been the President of Italy since 2022?",
    "answer": "Sergio Mattarella"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who held the world record for men's pole vault?",
    "answer": "Sergey Bubka"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who initiated the reforms in Japan during the Meiji period?",
    "answer": "Emperor Meiji"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who invented the first microscope?",
    "answer": "Antonie van Leeuwenhoek"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is 'Shevchenko' in chess?",
    "answer": "Andrey Shevchenko"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is a famous figure skater who has won World Championships?",
    "answer": "Evgeni Plushenko"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is considered the founder of Symbolism?",
    "answer": "Charles Baudelaire"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is considered the king of avant-garde fashion?",
    "answer": "Alexander McQueen"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is considered the main reformer of Christianity?",
    "answer": "Martin Luther"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is known as the King of the Marathon?",
    "answer": "Haile Gebrselassie"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is known as the painter of Venice, who created 'Parnassus' and 'The Procession of the Trojan Women'?",
    "answer": "Giovanni Bellini"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is known for their 'Splashes'?",
    "answer": "Jackson Pollock"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is known for their explorations of Africa?",
    "answer": "David Livingstone"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is known for their principle of least time?",
    "answer": "Pierre de Fermat"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is known for their work with geometric patterns and linear prints?",
    "answer": "Ettore Sottsass"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of 'Dead Souls'?",
    "answer": "Nikolai Gogol"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of 'Demons'?",
    "answer": "F. Dostoevsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of 'Doctor Zhivago'?",
    "answer": "Boris Pasternak"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of 'The Brothers Karamazov'?",
    "answer": "Fyodor Dostoevsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of 'The Yawning Heights'?",
    "answer": "Alexander Zinoviev"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of 'Ulysses'?",
    "answer": "James Joyce"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of 'Verses About the Beautiful Lady'?",
    "answer": "Blok"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel 'Dunya'?",
    "answer": "Green"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel 'Earthly Sadness'?",
    "answer": "Tatyana Ostapova"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel 'Two Lives'?",
    "answer": "Concordia Antarova"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the poem \"Lucifer\"?",
    "answer": "Juliusz Słowacki"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the poem 'Silent Night'?",
    "answer": "Iraida Danilova"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the sacred texts in Hinduism?",
    "answer": "Vyasa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the work 'Clean Monday'?",
    "answer": "Ivan Bunin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the work 'The Garden of Earthly Delights'?",
    "answer": "Hieronymus Bosch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the composer of the 'Fantastic Symphony'?",
    "answer": "Hector Berlioz"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the composer of the 'Mass in B minor'?",
    "answer": "Johann Sebastian Bach"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the director of the film 'The Hateful Eight'?",
    "answer": "Quentin Tarantino"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the director of the movie 'Fight Club'?",
    "answer": "David Fincher"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the director of the movie 'Parasite'?",
    "answer": "Bong Joon-ho"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the director of the movie 'The Dark Tower'?",
    "answer": "Nikolaj Arcel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the famous long-distance runner?",
    "answer": "Haile Gebrselassie"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the founder of Gothic fashion style?",
    "answer": "Gothic fashion does not have a specific founder"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the founder of the Diesel brand?",
    "answer": "Renzo Rosso"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the main figure in Confucianism?",
    "answer": "Confucius"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the most successful winter athlete with 8 Olympic gold medals?",
    "answer": "Bjørn Dæhlie"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the most successful woman in the history of tennis?",
    "answer": "Margaret Court"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the spiritual leader of Shintoism?",
    "answer": "Emperor of Japan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who laid the foundations of quantitative genetics?",
    "answer": "Ronald Fisher"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who led Cambodia before Pol Pot?",
    "answer": "Norodom Sihanouk"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who led France after the fall of Napoleon?",
    "answer": "Louis XVIII"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who led Yugoslavia after Tito?",
    "answer": "Lazar Koliševski"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who led the Children's Crusade?",
    "answer": "Stephen of Cloyes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who led the Confederate army in the American Civil War?",
    "answer": "Robert E. Lee"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who led the fashion house Dior after Christian Dior?",
    "answer": "Yves Saint Laurent"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who led the women's rights movement in the United Kingdom?",
    "answer": "Emmeline Pankhurst"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who painted 'Autumn Rhythm'?",
    "answer": "Jackson Pollock"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who painted 'The Grape Harvesters'?",
    "answer": "Pissarro"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who painted 'The Wounded Angel'?",
    "answer": "Hugo Simberg"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who painted the self-portrait with a distorted face?",
    "answer": "Egon Schiele"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who played Norman Bates in the movie 'Psycho'?",
    "answer": "Anthony Perkins"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who played Vito Corleone in the movie 'The Godfather'?",
    "answer": "Marlon Brando"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who played the lead role in the movie '2001: A Space Odyssey'?",
    "answer": "Keir Dullea"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who played the lead role in the movie 'Drive'?",
    "answer": "Ryan Gosling"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who played the lead role in the movie 'The Big Short'?",
    "answer": "Christian Bale"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who played the main role in the movie 'Knockin' on Heaven's Door'?",
    "answer": "Til Schweiger"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who popularized the punk style in fashion?",
    "answer": "Vivienne Westwood"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who predicted the existence of gravitational waves?",
    "answer": "Einstein"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who proposed the concept of sociometry?",
    "answer": "Jacob Moreno"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who proposed the idea of a neutron star?",
    "answer": "Landau"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who proposed the idea of the existence of black holes?",
    "answer": "John Michell"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who proposed the uncertainty principle?",
    "answer": "Werner Heisenberg"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who ratified the United States Constitution in 1787?",
    "answer": "George Washington"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who said 'Eli, Eli, Lama Sabachthani'?",
    "answer": "Jesus Christ"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was Reverend Varlaam of Khutyn?",
    "answer": "Saint"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was Saint Patrick?",
    "answer": "Missionary"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was a famous cartographer of the Renaissance?",
    "answer": "Gerardus Mercator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was awarded the first Nobel Prize in Physics?",
    "answer": "Wilhelm Röntgen"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was famous for their humility in the Christian tradition?",
    "answer": "Seraphim of Sarov"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was known as the author of 'New Zealand'?",
    "answer": "Jules Ferry"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was one of the famous architects of Saint Petersburg?",
    "answer": "Bartolomeo Rastrelli"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the 19th-century Russian revolutionary involved in the 'Trial of the 193'?",
    "answer": "Sofya Perovskaya"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Emperor of the Holy Roman Empire in 800 AD?",
    "answer": "Charlemagne"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Indian reformer of the 19th century?",
    "answer": "Ram Mohan Roy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the King of England during the Battle of Hastings?",
    "answer": "Harold II"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the King of France in the 13th century?",
    "answer": "Louis IX"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the President of Egypt during the signing of the Camp David Accords?",
    "answer": "Anwar Sadat"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the President of France during World War I?",
    "answer": "Raymond Poincaré"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the President of France from 1981 to 1995?",
    "answer": "François Mitterrand"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the President of Mexico from 1934 to 1940?",
    "answer": "Lázaro Cárdenas"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the President of Nigeria in 2015?",
    "answer": "Muhammadu Buhari"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the President of Poland in 1989?",
    "answer": "Wojciech Jaruzelski"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Prime Minister of India from 1947 to 1964?",
    "answer": "Jawaharlal Nehru"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Secretary-General of the United Nations in 1990?",
    "answer": "Javier Pérez de Cuéllar"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the author of 'The Decameron'?",
    "answer": "Giovanni Boccaccio"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the captain of the Afghanistan national football team in 2008?",
    "answer": "Zainuddin Nazir"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the center of reforms in Geneva?",
    "answer": "John Calvin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the chief architect of the Notre-Dame Cathedral?",
    "answer": "Jean de Chelles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the director of the film 'A Better Life'?",
    "answer": "Tony Kaye"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the face of Chanel No. 5 in the 1980s?",
    "answer": "Catherine Deneuve"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the famous Eastern conqueror?",
    "answer": "Tamerlane"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the famous cyclist who won the Tour de France a record number of times?",
    "answer": "Lance Armstrong"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the famous golfer who won 5 major titles?",
    "answer": "Arnold Palmer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Eastern Patriarch?",
    "answer": "Antiochian"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Olympic champion in the marathon?",
    "answer": "Spyridon Louis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Patriarch of Moscow?",
    "answer": "Job"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first President of Afghanistan?",
    "answer": "Mohammed Daoud Khan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of the United Kingdom?",
    "answer": "Robert Walpole"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Russian saint?",
    "answer": "Vladimir the Red Sun"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first emperor of China?",
    "answer": "Qin Shi Huang"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first female fencer to win three Olympic gold medals?",
    "answer": "Valentina Vezzali"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first president of Georgia?",
    "answer": "Zviad Gamsakhurdia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first president of South Korea?",
    "answer": "Syngman Rhee"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first to introduce the 'haute couture' collection?",
    "answer": "Charles Worth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first to measure the speed of light?",
    "answer": "Ole Rømer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first winner of the Tour de France?",
    "answer": "Maurice Garin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first woman to land a quadruple toe loop in figure skating?",
    "answer": "Alexandra Trusova"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the founder of Presbyterianism?",
    "answer": "John Knox"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the initiator of the Silk Road for the spread of Buddhism?",
    "answer": "Xuanzang"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the king of France during the French Revolution?",
    "answer": "Louis XVI"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the leader of Iran since 1979?",
    "answer": "Ruhollah Khomeini"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the leader of Norway from 1997 to 2000?",
    "answer": "Kjell Magne Bondevik"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the leader of the Reformation in Switzerland?",
    "answer": "Ulrich Zwingli"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the leader of the first Guinean revolution?",
    "answer": "Ahmed Sékou Touré"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the legendary coach of the Italian national team in 1982?",
    "answer": "Enzo Bearzot"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the legendary rugby player and captain of the New Zealand national team?",
    "answer": "Richie McCaw"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the president of Peru in 2001?",
    "answer": "Alejandro Toledo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won 5 consecutive Wimbledon titles?",
    "answer": "Björn Borg"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won 7 World Cup titles in cross-country skiing?",
    "answer": "Johannes Klæbo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won 8 gold medals at the Olympics?",
    "answer": "Michael Phelps"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won five consecutive Tour de France titles from 1991 to 1995?",
    "answer": "Miguel Indurain"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the Battle of Waterloo?",
    "answer": "Wellington"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'Children of the Arbat'?",
    "answer": "Anatoly Rybakov"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'Hamlet'?",
    "answer": "William Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'I Am That'?",
    "answer": "Nisargadatta"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'Proletarian Leaders'?",
    "answer": "Viktor Nekrasov"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'Shogun'?",
    "answer": "James Clavell"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'The City of God'?",
    "answer": "Augustine of Hippo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'The Masterpiece'?",
    "answer": "Rockwell"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'The Mysterious Soul'?",
    "answer": "Tsvetaeva"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'The Sad Knights'?",
    "answer": "Petrov-Vodkin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'The Scaffold'?",
    "answer": "Chingiz Aitmatov"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote 'The Twelve Labors of Hercules'?",
    "answer": "Unknown author"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote parts of the Old Testament?",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the national anthem of the USA?",
    "answer": "Francis Scott Key"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the novel 'American Pastoral'?",
    "answer": "Philip Roth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the play 'Boris Godunov'?",
    "answer": "A. Pushkin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the screenplay for the movie \"Schindler's List\"?",
    "answer": "Steven Zaillian"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the series 'Salon Scenes'?",
    "answer": "Adolph Menzel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the treatise 'Confessions'?",
    "answer": "Augustine of Hippo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the treatise 'The Way to Poverty'?",
    "answer": "Symeon the New Theologian"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the work 'The Forgotten Path'?",
    "answer": "Elena Nekrasova"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who, according to religious tradition, wrote the Torah?",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "question": "With which field of study is Charles Lyell associated?",
    "answer": "Geology"
  }
]